Guide to the Jeanne R. Lowe Papers, circa 1941-1972
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series II. Writings, 1946-1972
  - Continuing Education for Women: Report for the Sloan Foundation (1971)
    - Research
      - Individual Institutions: George Washington University, 1971 (Folder 10.22)
      - Individual Institutions: Loyola University, 1971 (Folder 10.23)
      - Individual Institutions: Northeastern University, 1971 (Folder 10.24)
      - Individual Institutions: Radcliffe Institute, 1971 (Folder 10.25)
      - Individual Institutions: Sarah Lawrence College, 1971 (Folder 10.26)
      - Individual Institutions: Simmons College, 1971 (Folder 10.27)
      - Individual Institutions: Syracuse University College, 1971 (Folder 11.1)
      - Individual Institutions: Tufts University, 1971 (Folder 11.2)
      - Individual Institutions: University of Michigan, 1971 (Folder 11.3)
      - Individual Institutions: University of Minnesota, 1971 (Folder 11.4)
      - Individual Institutions: University of Pennsylvania, 1971 (Folder 11.5)
      - Individual Institutions: University of Pittsburgh, 1971 (Folder 11.6)
      - Individual Institutions: University of Wisconsin, 1971 (Folder 11.7)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1971 (Folder 11.8)
      - Miscellaneous publications, 1965-1969 (Folder 11.9)
      - Miscellaneous publications, 1970-1971 (Folder 11.10)
  - MacMillan Book
    - Bibliography drafts, 1970 (Folder 11.11)
    - Chapter outlines, undated (Folder 11.12)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Folder 11.13)
    - Drafts - Proposal and Chapters 1-5, 1970 (Folder 11.14)
    - Drafts - Chapters 1-4, undated (Folder 11.15)
    - Drafts - Chapter 1, 1970 (Folder 11.16)
    - Drafts - Chapter 2, 1970 (Folder 11.17)
    - Drafts - Chapter 3, 1970 (Folder 11.18)
    - Drafts - Chapter 4, with notes, 1970 (Folders 11.19-11.20)
    - Drafts - Chapter 5, with notes, undated (Folders 11.21-11.22)
    - Drafts - Chapter 5, notes and clippings, 1970 (Folder 11.23)
    - Drafts - Chapter 6, 1970 (Folder 11.24)
    - Drafts - Chapter 7, 1970 (Folder 11.25)
    - Drafts - Chapter 8, 1970 (Folder 11.26)
    - Drafts and notes, 1970 (Folder 11.27)
    - Notes, 1970 (Folders 11.28-11.29)
    - Notes - "Urban Living: Value of Bigness vs Problems of Size", 1970 (Folder 11.30)
    - Notes - "Why Cities Are in Trouble", undated (Folder 11.31)
    - Research, clippings, 1971 (Folder 11.32)
    - Research, "crime", 1970 (Folder 11.33)
    - Research, "Grade 8 Urban Growth…Calendar of Lessons", 1970 (Folder 11.34)
    - Research, "Grade 8 Urban Growth…Course of Study and Related Learning Activities…", 1968-1969 (Folder 11.35)
  - The Near Side of Federalism (Ford Foundation Report)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Folder 11.36)
    - Drafts, outline, 1967 (Folder 11.37)
    - Drafts, "first draft", 1967 Dec (Folder 11.38)
    - Draft, circa 1968 (Folder 12.1)
    - Draft, 1968 Jul (Folder 12.2)
    - Draft, revisions, 1968 Aug (Folder 12.3)
    - Draft, 1969 Feb (Folder 12.4)
    - Draft, 1969 Jun 24 (Folder 12.5)
    - Draft with revisions, 1971 Jun (Folder 12.6)
    - Draft, 1971 Sep (Folder 12.7)
    - Notes, circa 1968 (Folder 12.8)
  - New York University Survey of Secondary Schools
    - Correspondence with publishers, 1971 (Folder 12.9)
    - Correspondence with school districts, 1971 (Folder 12.10)
    - Correspondence with State Department of Education, 1971 (Folder 12.11)
    - Correspondence, urban affairs curriculum, 1969-1971 (Folder 12.12)
    - Notes, urban affairs curriculum, 1970-1971 (Folder 12.13)
    - Research, Chicago, 1971 (Folder 12.14)
    - Research, Detroit Public Schools, 1971 (Folder 12.15)
    - Research, Indianapolis, 1971 (Folder 12.16)
    - Research, Seattle Public Schools, 1971 (Folder 12.17)
  - Other Writings
    - "85 Million Live in US Slums" (The Tulsa Tribune), clipping, 1958 (Folder 12.18)
    - "Adequate, Open Housing in Metropolis: Comprehensive Area Management's Challenge to the Business Community (National Association of Manufacturers, Area Industrial Problems Committee), drafts, 1967-1968 (Folder 12.19)
    - "The American House," article on property tax reform, notes, 1965 (Folder 12.20)
    - "Balanced [Neighborhoods]," notes and drafts, circa 1961 (Folder 12.21)
    - "Balanced [Neighborhoods]," research, 1962 (Folders 12.22-12.23)
    - "Battle Against Blight: Remaking Our Cities" (North American Newspaper Alliance), proofs, 1958 (Folder 12.24)
    - "Can Americans Create a City of Joy?" in the Proceedings of the 44th Annual Congress of Cities of the National League of Cities, 1967 (Folder 12.25)
    - "Cities in Crisis" (Journal of National Association of Women Deans and Counselors), clippings, 1968 (Folder 12.26)
    - "Clearance Plans Promise Results" (The Chattanooga Times), clipping, 1958 (Folder 12.27)
    - "Community Facilities and Services" for James Scheuer, 1958 (Folder 12.28)
    - "Downtown Areas: Mess to Malls" (The Tulsa Tribune), clipping, 1958 (Folder 12.29)
    - "European vs American Urban Policy," for the 20th Century Fund, draft, 1970 (Folder 12.30)
    - "Federal Renewal Program Aids in Slum Clearance" (Syracuse Herald-Journal), clipping, undated (Folder 12.31)
    - Film proposal - "New Life for American Cities: A Case Study - New Haven, CT," draft with correspondence, 1958 (Folder 12.32)
    - "Fort Worth Forgot to Remember the Citizen" (Journal of Housing), clippings, 1959 (Folder 12.33)
    - "Greenwich - LWU speech," notes and research, 1968 (Folder 12.34)
    - "Higbee ms" for the 20th Century Fund, draft, 1967 (Folder 12.35)
    - "Hofstra College and Long Island," draft, 1957 (Folder 12.36)
    - "Housing and Urban Change: Where Does Social Work Fit In," speech for University of Chicago School of Social Service Administration, draft, 1970 (Folder 12.37)
    - "Housing and Urban Change: Where Does Social Work Fit In" (The Social Service Review), clippings, 1970-1971 (Folder 12.38)
    - "Last Test for Federalism" (THINK Magazine), drafts, 1970 (Folder 12.39)
    - "Lee of New Haven and His Political Inkpot" (Harper's Magazine), clippings, 1957 (Folder 12.40)
    - "Local Funds Put to Worth Building Up Downtowns" (Syracuse Herald-Journal), clipping, 1958 (Folder 13.1)
    - LOOK Magazine, CPI article, draft, 1963-1965 (Folder 13.2)
    - "'Lowe' Program for Cities," drafts, 1967 (Folder 13.3)
    - "Major Overhaul Needed in Cities" (The Chattanooga Times), clipping, 1958 (Folder 13.4)
    - McCall's Magazine - Article, drafts and correspondence, 1968 (Folder 13.5)
    - McCall's Magazine - Articles and editorials, clippings, 1967-1968 (Folder 37.3 (Oversize))
    - "A Metropolitan Strategy for the Private Sector" (The Saturday Review), drafts, undated (Folder 13.6)
    - Miscellaneous speech notes, undated (Folder 13.7)
    - National Association of Women Deans and Counselors, speech, drafts, 1968 (Folder 13.8)
    - National Association of Women Deans and Counselors, speech, notes and research, 1968 (Folder 13.9)
    - National Commission on Urban Problems (Douglas Commission), Lowe testimony, 1967 (Folder 13.10)
    - The Nation, "New Coalition," drafts and notes, 1957 (Folder 13.11)
    - The Nation, "New Coalition," draft with correspondence, 1957 (Folder 13.12)
    - "New Life for Aging Neighborhoods" (America Illustrated), 1958-1959 (Folder 13.13)
    - "The Negro Woman," drafts and research, 1968 (Folder 13.14)
    - "NY Urban Development Company Proposal" for the 20th Century Fund, draft, 1970-1971 (Folder 13.15)
    - Notebook - Economics Meeting, census, etc., undated (Folder 13.16)
    - Notebook - RPA meeting, 1961-1962 (Folder 13.17)
    - Notes - "Andrew Haswell Green", 1958 (Folder 13.18)
    - Notes - "Buffalo, [NY] - Alinsky", 1965 (Folder 13.19)
    - Notes - "case histories", 1970 (Folder 13.20)
    - Notes - "Future projects", 1965-1966 (Folder 13.21)
    - Notes - "Possible projects", 1962-1970 (Folder 13.22)
    - Notes - "Story ideas", 1957-1959 (Folder 13.23)
    - Notes - "Writer's job", 1964, undated (Folder 13.24)
    - "Old Cities and New Towns" in The Saturday Review, 1968 Apr (Folder 13.25)
    - "Our Urban Crisis," speech notes, undated (Folder 13.26)
    - Pennsylvania Planning Association Annual Meeting, speech drafts, 1957 (Folder 13.27)
    - "The Press Takes a Long-Range Look at Urban Renewal" (NAHRO Convention), drafts, undated (Folder 13.28)
    - "Progress Report on Cities" (National American Newspaper Alliance), proofs, 1958 (Folder 13.29)
    - "Race, Jobs, and Cities: What Business Can Do," for The Saturday Review, drafts and correspondence, 1968-1969 (Folder 13.30)
    - "Race, Jobs, and Cities: What Business Can Do" (The Saturday Review), clippings, 1969 (Folder 13.31)
    - "Rebuilding Cities - and Politics" (The Nation), clipping, 1958 (Folder 13.32)
    - "Rebuilding Cities - and Politics" (The Nation), reviews, 1958 (Folder 13.33)
    - Sermon before the First Unitarian Church of Cleveland, drafts and notes, 1969 Nov 9 (Folders 14.1-14.2)
    - "Special To: Women's News Service," draft, undated (Folder 14.3)
    - "The States, Will They Act to Save Our Cities?" for THINK, clipping, 1970 Mar-Apr (Folder 14.4)
    - "The States, Will They Act to Save Our Cities?" for THINK, correspondence and drafts, 1969-1970 (Folder 14.5)
    - "The States, Will They Act to Save Our Cities?" for THINK, notebooks, 1969 (Folder 14.6)
    - "The States, Will They Act to Save Our Cities?" for THINK, research, Buffalo-Amherst Corridor, 1969 (Folder 14.7)
    - "The States, Will They Act to Save Our Cities?" for THINK, research, Lysander, NY "New Community", 1969 (Folder 14.8)
    - "The States, Will They Act to Save Our Cities?" for THINK, research, Mid-Hudson Pattern for Progress, Inc., 1969 (Folder 14.9)
    - "The States, Will They Act to Save Our Cities?" for THINK, research, NY Urban Development Corporation, 1969 (Folder 14.10)
    - "The States, Will They Act to Save Our Cities?" for THINK, research, "Welfare Island", 1969 (Folder 14.11)
    - "Travel in Egypt," draft, circa 1947 (Folder 14.12)
    - "Travel in Egypt" (for New York Times), draft, circa 1952 (Folder 14.13)
    - "Urban Renewal," draft, undated (Folder 14.14)
    - "The University and the Emerging Federalism" conference, speech drafts, 1972 (Folder 14.15)
    - "Victor Gruen," drafts, undated (Folder 14.16)
    - "Washington's 'Operation Exodus'" (Reader's Digest), draft, undated (Folder 14.17)
    - "What Rehabilitation Can Do (and Can't Do) to Uplift People as Well as Houses" (House & Home), clipping, 1959 (Folder 14.18)
    - "What White America Must Do" (The Saturday Review), clipping, 1968 (Folder 14.19)
    - "What's Happened in Fort Worth?" drafts and research, 1959-1960 (Folder 14.20)
    - "What's Happened in Fort Worth?" (Architectural Forum), clipping, 1959 (Folder 14.21)
    - Writings by Others - Gleklen, Donald and John Taussig, "A Case Study of Manhattan Town," draft with notes by Jeanne Lowe, 1963 (Folder 14.22)
- Series III. Projects and Research by City, 1943-1972
  - Baltimore, MD
    - Notes and research, 1961 (Folder 14.23)
  - Chicago, IL
    - Hyde Park, correspondence and notes, 1958-1961 (Folder 14.24)
    - Hyde Park, Kenwood Community Conference, 1954-1960 (Folder 14.25)
    - Hyde Park, notebooks #1-2, circa 1960 (Folder 14.26)
    - Hyde Park, notebooks #3-4, circa 1960 (Folder 14.27)
    - Hyde Park, research, 1956-1958 (Folder 14.28)
    - Hyde Park, research, 1958 (Folder 14.29)
    - Hyde Park, research and notes, 1960-1961 (Folder 15.1)
    - Hyde Park, research and notes, 1961 (Folder 15.2)
    - Hyde Park, urban renewal, research and notes, 1961 (Folder 15.3)
    - "Urban Renewal Plan: Near West Side, City of Chicago", 1960 Oct 20 (Folder 15.4)
  - Cleveland, OH
    - Notes and research, 1956-1961 (Folder 15.5)
  - Fresno, CA
    - Notes and research, 1960 (Folder 15.6)
  - Miami, FL
    - Notebooks #1-2, undated (Folder 15.7)
    - Notebooks #3-4, undated (Folder 15.8)
    - Notebooks, undated (Folder 15.9)
    - Notes, undated (Folder 15.10)
    - Research - General, 1961 (Folder 15.11)
    - Research - Campbell firing, Oct 17 election, 1961 (Folder 15.12)
    - Research - Dade County Board of Commissioners, Meeting of Nov 22, 1960 - Index (Folder 15.13)
    - Research - Dade County reports, 1958-1961 (Folder 15.14)
    - Research - Dade County research, ephemera, circa 1957 (Folder 15.15)
    - Research - Islandia, 1961 (Folder 15.16)
    - Research - Land use, notes and research, 1961 (Folder 15.17)
    - Research - MacLeod, 1961 (Folder 15.18)
    - Research - Miami Metro, clippings, 1961 (Folder 15.19)
    - Research - Miami Metro, notes and research, 1947-1961 (Folder 15.20)
    - Research - Miami Metro, notes and research, 1958-1961 (Folder 15.21)
    - Research - Miami Metro, notes and research, 1958-1962 (Folder 15.22)
    - Research - "Metro Bulletin", 1960-1961 (Folder 16.1)
    - Research - Metropolitan Dade County Planning Dept, Planning Staff Reports #1-6, 1960 (Folder 16.2)
    - Research - Reassessment, 1961 (Folder 16.3)
  - New Haven, CT
    - Drafts, notes, and correspondence, 1954-1959 (Folder 16.4)
    - Drafts, notes, and research, 1957 (Folder 16.5)
    - Drafts and notes, 1962 (Folder 16.6)
    - Drafts, notes, and research, 1962-1963 (Folder 16.7)
    - Drafts and notes, undated (Folder 16.8)
    - Drafts, notes, and research - Church St, 1957-1963 (Folder 16.9)
    - Drafts and notes, "Lee of New Haven and His Political Jackpot", 1957-1962 (Folder 16.10)
    - Drafts, "The Real Revolution", undated (Folder 16.11)
    - Drafts, notes, and research - Wooster Square manuscript, 1961-1962 (Folder 16.12)
    - Notebook, 1961 (Folder 16.13)
    - Notebooks, 1961-1962 (Folder 16.14)
    - Notebooks, [1965?] Nov (Folder 16.15)
    - Notebooks, 1966 (Folder 16.16)
    - Notebooks, undated (Folder 16.17)
    - Notes, undated (Folder 16.18)
    - Notes - Books about New Haven, undated (Folder 16.19)
    - Notes and research, 1961-1962 (Folder 16.20)
    - Notes and research, 1962-1963 (Folder 16.21)
    - Notes and research, 1964-1965 (Folder 16.22)
    - Notes and research, 1965 (Folder 17.1)
    - Notes and research - Church St, 1959-1963 (Folder 17.2)
    - Notes and research - Church St, 1962 (Folder 17.3)
    - Notes and research - Community Progress, Inc. (CPI) and employment, 1964 (Folder 17.4)
    - Notes and research - Community Progress, Inc. (CPI), 1965 (Folder 17.5)
    - Notes and research - Conclusion, 1964 (Folder 17.6)
    - Notes and research - Dixwell redevelopment, 1960-1962 (Folder 17.7)
    - Notes and research - Ford Foundation, gray areas, 1962-1965 (Folder 17.8)
    - Notes and research - Harper's Magazine article background, undated (Folder 17.9)
    - Notes and research - Housing, 1962 (Folder 17.10)
    - Notes and research - Mayor Lee, 1957-1962 (Folder 17.11)
    - Notes and research - Mayor Lee, 1951-1961 (Folder 17.12)
    - Notes and research - Urban renewal, other cities, 1956-1960 (Folder 17.13)
    - Notes and research - "Middle Ground", 1961 (Folder 17.14)
    - Notes and research - Mitchell Svirdoff, 1962-1964 (Folder 17.15)
    - Notes and research - Planning and redevelopment, 1955-1957 (Folder 17.16)
    - Notes and research - "schools", 1961-1963 (Folders 17.17-17.18)
    - Research, 1954-1961 (Folder 18.1)
    - Research, 1955-1960 (Folder 18.2)
    - Research, 1960 (Folder 18.3)
    - Research, 1960-1963 (Folder 18.4)
    - Research, 1963-1965 (Folder 18.5)
    - Research, 1964-1965 (Folder 18.6)
    - Research - "Addresses by: Hon. Richard C. Lee, Eugene V. Rostow", 1959 (Folder 18.7)
    - Research - Business relocation payments, 1960 (Folder 18.8)
    - Research - Citizen's Action Commission, 1957-1960 (Folder 18.9)
    - Research - Citywide Recreation Survey, 1961 (Folder 18.10)
    - Research - Community Council of Greater New Haven, report, 1963 (Folder 18.11)
    - Research - Community Progress, Inc., 1963-1964 (Folder 18.12)
    - Research - Dixwell redevelopment, 1959-1960 (Folder 18.13)
    - Research - Dixwell redevelopment, undated (Folder 18.14)
    - Research - Redevelopment Agency, annual reports, 1963-1964 (Folder 18.15)
    - Research - Redevelopment Agency, publications, 1963-1964 (Folder 18.16)
    - Research - Wooster Square, 1957-1963 (Folder 19.1)
    - Research - "Wooster Square Redevelopment and Renewal Plan", 1958 Jun 2 (Folder 19.2)
  - New York, NY
    - The Architect's Technical Assistance Center, 1971 (Folder 19.3)
    - Chelsea - Notebooks, undated (Folder 19.4)
    - Chelsea - Notes and research, 1960-1961 (Folder 19.5)
    - Citizen's Housing and Planning Council of NY, Inc., publications, 1960 (Folder 19.6)
    - Citizens Union - planning committee, 1963 (Folder 19.7)
    - Citizens Union - "Proposal for Decentralizing City Government", 1961 (Folder 19.8)
    - Department of City Planning, newsletter, 1958-1963 (Folder 19.9)
    - Fund for the City of New York - Contract, 1971 Oct (Folder 19.10)
    - Fund for the City of New York - "Housing Statistics Handbook", 1971-1972 (Folder 19.11)
    - Fund for the City of New York - Report, drafts and notes, 1971 (Folder 19.12)
    - Fund for the City of New York - Report, notebooks, 1971 (Folders 19.13-19.14)
    - Fund for the City of New York - Report, notebooks, undated (Folder 19.15)
    - Fund for the City of New York - Report, notes and research, 1971 (Folders 19.16-19.17)
    - "Housing," notes and research, 1963-1966 (Folder 19.18)
    - "Housing," research, 1959-1963 (Folders 19.19-19.21)
    - "Housing," research, 1965-1966 (Folder 19.22)
    - "Housing," research - "An Interim Report on Neighborhood Conservation in New York City", 1963 (Folder 19.23)
    - "Housing and slums," research, 1957-1962 (Folder 20.1)
    - Housing and Development Board - notes and research, 1959-1962 (Folder 20.2)
    - Housing and Development Board - notes and research, 1962-1963 (Folder 20.3)
    - Housing and Development Board - research, 1960-1965 (Folder 20.4)
    - Housing and Development Board - research, 1961-1966 (Folder 20.5)
    - Housing and Development Board - "West Side Urban Renewal Area Project No. NY R-43", 1963 (Folder 20.6)
    - Housing and Development Board - "West Side Urban Renewal Project", 1959-1961 (Folder 20.7)
    - Housing and Development Board - West Village project, 1959-1962 (Folder 20.8)
    - Housing Authority - Report, correspondence, 1968-1969 (Folder 20.9)
    - Housing Authority - Report, draft, 1969 May (Folder 20.10)
    - Housing Authority - Report, final draft, 1969 Aug (Folder 20.11)
    - Metropolitan Regional Council, research, 1962 (Folder 20.12)
    - The Municipal Art Society of New York, 1970-1972 (Folder 20.13)
    - The Municipal Art Society of New York, awards committee, 1971 (Folder 20.14)
    - The Municipal Art Society of New York, subway art, 1970 (Folder 20.15)
    - National Association of County Officials - Meeting, notes and papers, 1962 Jul (Folder 20.16)
    - "New Towns - Federal Programs," research, 1965 (Folder 20.17)
    - "New York City and Robert Moses"
      - Drafts, notes, and research, 1963-1965 (Folder 20.18)
      - Notebooks, undated (Folder 20.19)
      - Notes and research, 1958-1963 (Folders 20.20-20.22)
      - Notes and research, 1958-1964 (Folder 20.23)
      - Notes and research, 1960 (Folder 20.24)
      - Notes and research, 1960-1963 (Folder 20.25)
      - Notes and research, 1960-1965 (Folder 20.26)
      - Notes and research, 1961 (Folder 20.27)
      - Notes and research, 1961-1966 (Folder 21.1)
      - 1959 scandal, notes and research, 1959, 1963 (Folder 21.2)
      - "The End Product," notes and research, 1965 (Folder 21.3)
      - New York method, notes and research, 1963 (Folder 21.4)
      - Slums and relocation, notes and research, 1956-1963 (Folder 21.5)
      - Start of Title I, notes and research, 1949-1960 (Folder 21.6)
    - New York City, notes and research, 1961-1963 (Folder 21.7)
    - New York Regional Plan Association - "Choices for '76," proposal on urban planning, 1971 May 11 (Folder 21.8)
    - Radio WMCA - "The Housing That Haunts New York," scripts, 1963 (Folder 21.9)
    - "State government and metropolitan planning," research, 1966-1971 (Folder 21.10)
    - Taxes and revenue, research, 1960-1964 (Folder 21.11)
    - "Triborough Bridge," notes and research, 1956-1958 (Folder 21.12)
    - The Urban Coalition
      - House & Home roundtable conference, correspondence, 1969 (Folder 21.13)
      - House & Home roundtable conference, research, 1968-1969 (Folder 21.14)
      - House & Home roundtable conference, "Urban Housing: Patterns for Corporate Action," drafts and notes, 1969 (Folder 21.15)
      - Urban America, Inc. Development Forum 6, ephemera and correspondence, 1969 Apr (Folder 21.16)
      - Urban America, Inc. Development Forum 6, notes, 1969 Apr (Folder 21.17)
      - Urban America, Inc. Development Forum 6, "The Corporation and Low-Income Housing", 1969 Aug (Folder 21.18)
    - The Urban Coalition Study
      - College Board Corporation, 1969 (Folder 21.19)
      - Correspondence on Position Papers and Statement of Principles of the National Urban Coalition, 1969 Apr-Sep (Folder 21.20)
      - Letter to university president, drafts, 1969 Apr (Folder 21.21)
      - National Urban Coalition goals and principles, research and notes, 1969 (Folder 21.22)
      - Notes, undated (Folder 21.23)
      - Notes and research, 1969 (Folder 21.24)
      - Phase II research, correspondence, 1969 (Folder 21.25)
      - Phase II research, C.U.N.Y., 1967-1969 (Folder 21.26)
      - Phase II research, Columbia University, 1968-1969 (Folder 21.27)
      - Phase II research, Fordham University, 1968-1969 (Folder 21.28)
      - Phase II research, New York University, 1968-1969 (Folder 21.29)
      - Phase II research, Teachers College, Columbia University, 1968-1969 (Folder 22.1)
      - Phase II research, urban universities: admissions, educational programs, special studies, 1969 (Folder 22.2)
      - Planning drafts, 1969 (Folder 22.3)
      - Press release, 1969 (Folder 22.4)
      - Proposal, 1969 Mar (Folder 22.5)
      - Reports, 1969 (Folder 22.6)
      - Reports, interim report, 1970 Feb (Folder 22.7)
      - Reports, synopsis of findings, 1970 Apr (Folder 22.8)
      - University personnel notes, 1969 (Folder 22.9)
    - "What's Wrong with NYC?" notes and research, 1955-1963 (Folder 22.10)
    - Zoning, notes and research, 1959-1963 (Folder 22.11)
  - Oakland, CA
    - Research, 1960 (Folder 22.12)
  - Philadelphia, PA
    - General - Drafts and notes, 1959-1960 (Folder 22.13)
    - General - Drafts and notes, "The Return of the Native", 1961 (Folder 22.14)
    - General - Notebooks, 1960 (Folder 22.15)
    - General - Notebooks, 1961-1962 (Folder 22.16)
    - General - Notebooks, circa 1961 (Folder 22.17)
    - General - Notebooks, 1965-1966 (Folder 22.18)
    - General - Notes and research, 1958-1961 (Folder 22.19)
    - General - Notes and research, 1960-1962 (Folder 22.20)
    - General - Notes and research, 1960-1965 (Folder 23.1)
    - General - Notes and research, 1963-1965 (Folder 23.2)
    - Center City - Notes and research, 1958-1961 (Folder 23.3)
    - Center City - Notes and research, 1960-1965 (Folder 23.4)
    - Center City - Notes and research, undated (Folder 23.5)
    - "Commission on Human Relations," notes and research, 1956-1961 (Folder 23.6)
    - "Commission on Human Relations," informational packets #1-3, circa 1960 (Folder 23.7)
    - "Commission on Human Relations," informational packets #4, circa 1960 (Folder 23.8)
    - Commission on Human Relations, 1960-1962 (Folder 23.9)
    - Community Renewal Program, publications, 1964-1965 (Folder 23.10)
    - Community Renewal Program, "Technical Report #6", 1963 (Folder 23.11)
    - "Dilworth as Mayor," notes and research, 1950-1960 (Folder 23.12)
    - "Early Days," notes and research, 1951-1961 (Folder 23.13)